Portfolio: cslyons1.github.io/csl.github.io · LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cody-lyons

OBJECTIVE

Seeking to apply a decade of project management background, high-level communication skills, collaborative leadership approaches, and experience working in generative AI to effectively manage teams in pursuit of progressing the capabilities of advanced AI models.

WORK EXPERIENCE

xΔI Oct. 2024 - Current Remote

Human Data Team

- Developed, deployed, and continually maintain a division-wide project management communications system, keeping communications and project documentation for highly dynamic multimodal project teams efficient and cohesive while allowing five Team Leads to manage the workflows of more than 100 AI data trainers across seven projects simultaneously
- Created and refined our multimodal division onboarding procedures resulting in a 50% reduction in project onboarding time for new AI data trainers
- Manage and drive dynamic multimodal team workflows, delegating responsibility to ensure project milestones are met
- Introduced and monitored initiatives such as AI data trainer support strategies, fostering greater team alignment and collaboration
- Created and implemented a queue allocation code that evenly distributes AI data trainers to data queues based on past tasking metrics ensuring consistent depletion of queues allowing for more efficient data delivery to research teams - this has allowed data queues with initial disparities of greater than 300 tasks to be depleted simultaneously
- Create tools for tracking project-related items, enabling better communication of insights to researchers, supporting adjustments to generative AI model parameters
- Develop QA parameters of multimodal projects ensuring generative AI models are being trained in line with Researcher and Project Lead's project parameters
- Create and implement standard operating procedures for training generative AI models

Regency Commercial Construction

Dec. 2019 - Jan. 2023

Assistant Project Manager

Beltsville, MD

Executed project management duties on concurrent, large-scale projects within diverse teams of stakeholders including:

- Managed all aspects of multiple concurrent, dynamic projects, monitoring multi-faceted project data and actively adjusting schedules, budgets, and scopes of work to ensure milestones were met, resulting in early project turnover and increased profits
- Employed version control practices to develop, organize, and distribute project information to project teams
- Served as liaison between engineers, architects, stakeholders and subcontractors, maintaining communication between all parties, and facilitating positive working relationships that resulted in return work

ADP Consultants Feb. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Assistant Project Manager

Capitol Heights, MD

Performed project management duties on large-scale government projects and assisted company owner in the following:

- Tracked key project milestones and prepared status update documentation for presentation to stakeholders
- Created and reviewed project-specific documents for compliance with contract documents
- Facilitated communication with project stakeholders and maintained positive working relationships

Clark Concrete Contractors Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2018

Quality Control Engineer

Engineering Technician

Bethesda, MD

Collaborated with government agency stakeholders to manage project-specific quality control procedures including:

- Implemented project-specific document version control and access structures across large-scale, dynamic projects to regulate, update, and distribute project documents between stakeholders and project teams
- Developed and implemented quality control plans and presented related project data reports to stakeholders
- Reviewed and issued contract document submissions for approval

Hillis-Carnes Engineering Associates

Jul. 2008 - Sept. 2016

Annapolis Junction, MD

- Collaborated with stakeholders to create and implement quality control procedures on large-scale projects
- Developed detailed reports documenting operations, project and material-related issues, and solution proposals
- Upheld communication between stakeholders, contractors, and third-party consultants

Project Management, Effective Communication, Data Analysis, Python, Data Visualization, Creative Problem Solving

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

The Pennsylvania State University

Bachelor of Science, Integrated Social Sciences

Google Data Analytics

Professional Certificate in Data Analytics from Google